Dr. Jiangshan Yu (B.Eng, MSc, MPhil, PhD)

CONTACT

INFORMATION E02 0245-280,

Maison du Nombre,

University of Luxembourg, 2 Avenue de l'Universit,

L-4365, Esch-sur-Alzette,

Luxembourg.

E-mail:

j.yu.research@gmail.com

Home-page:

www.jiangshanyu.com

RESEARCH INTERESTS My research interests are in **cyber security and user privacy**. In particular, the focus of my research has been on applied crypto, secure authentication, key management, public key infrastructure, secure messaging, post-compromise security, and formal security verification.

EDUCATION

Ph.D in Cyber Security, Oct.2012-Sept.2016. **University of Birmingham**, UK.

Thesis: Mitigating private key compromise.

M.Phil in Cryptography (2011-2012). **University of Wollongong**, NSW, Australia. Thesis: *Remote User Authentication in Distributed Systems and Networks*.

M.Sc. in Information Security (2010-2011). University of Wollongong, Australia.

B.Eng. in Computer Science and Technology (2005-2009), **Northeast Agricultural University**, Harbin, China. (**Top 1 out of 82, Best Thesis Award**).

POSITIONS

Research fellow, Interdisciplinary Centre for Security, Reliability and Trust (SnT), University of Luxembourg, Luxembourg. (2016-Present)

Honorary research fellow, University of Birmingham, UK. (2016-Present)

Director, CloudTomo Limited, UK. (2014-2016)

Tech consultant, Jin Xin Tong Trust and Investment Corporation Ltd, UK. (2014-2015)

President, Endless Martial Arts Association, Wollongong, Australia. (2011-2012)

Manager, Department of Student Service, Wollongong Chinese Students & Scholars Association, Wollongong, NSW, Australia.(2010-2012)

SELECTED PROJECTS:

Co-Designer. Huawei SoC Secure Boot Solution, UK. 2016. (Funded by Huawei Ltd.)

Project manager. Innovate UK project on user-friendly security and privacy to increase confidence in cloud-based systems, UK. June - September, 2015. (Funded by Innovate UK.)

GRANT:

"Technology inspired feasibility study for secure email and cloud storage", GBP33,000 from Technology Strategy Board (Innovate UK), 2015.

PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES:

(Finalist) RAEng Enterprise Fellowship, Royal Academy of Engineering, UK. 2015.

Chair, The future of digital currency and block chain technology workshop, Birmingham, UK. September, 2015.

PC member, Software Architecture for Big Data and the Cloud, 2016.

Invited Reviewer (Journal):

• IEEE Transactions on Information Forensics & Security; The Computer Journal; Journal of Information Security and Applications; Security and Communication Networks; International Journal of Information Security.

Invited Reviewer (Conference):

 ACISP 2013; ESORICS 2013; DPM 2013; ACNS 2014; SEC 2014; FMS 2014; WPES 2014; POST (ETAPS) 2015; ASIACCS 2015; IFIP SEC 2015; IEEE Euro S&P 2016; ESSoS 2016; IFIP SEC 2016; ESORICS 2016; WISTP 2016; EuroSys 2017; AsiaCCS 2017.

PATENTS Key Usage Detection (Patent pending)

- UK Patent Application GB 1416188.9
- US Patent Application US 14/852,342

AWARDS Scholarships:

- Universitas 21 scholarship from the University of Birmingham, 2015.
- EPSRC project funding for PhD studies at University of Birmingham, 2012 2015.
- Overseas top-up scholarship from the University of Birmingham for PhD studies, 2012 - 2015.
- First class scholarship, Northeast Agricultural University, Harbin, Heilongjiang, China, 2006, 2007, and 2008.

Other:

- First place award, the Coniston poster competition, University of Birmingham, UK, 2014.
- Outstanding Graduates of Heilongjiang Province, Heilongjiang, China, 2009;
- Outstanding Graduates of Northeast Agricultural University, Harbin, Heilongjiang, China, 2009;
- Best Undergraduate Thesis Award, Northeast Agricultural University, Harbin, Heilongjiang, China, 2009;
- Outstanding Academic Award, The Northeast Agricultural University, China, 2008;
- First National Prize of China Contemporary Undergraduate Mathematical Contest in Modeling, China, 2007;
- **Second National Prize** of China Contemporary Undergraduate Mathematical Contest in Modeling, China, 2006;
- Outstanding Student Award of The Northeast Agricultural University, China, 2006;
- Outstanding Student Leadership Award, The Northeast Agricultural University, China, 2006.